

Davey Mason Web Developer

https://daveymason.com

Profile

Natural **problem solver** and strong passion for design and performance. A **quick learner**, that's dedicated to finding the right solution.

Over two years' experience designing websites and web apps using a range of technologies, responsible for the entire stack, speed and security of over 50 websites.

I'm currently looking for a position in which I could become a **Web Development expert**.

Tech Stack

HTML/CSS

Bootstrap

JavaScript

- React
- > iQuery
- Node

Php

- WordPress
- Laravel

MySQL

EDUCATION

Full-stack coding bootcamp

NuCamp (Online, remote) [2021]

Revised Bootstrap and the latest standards of **Javascript**. Studied **React**, **React Native**, **Node**, **Express**, **MongoDB** & **NPM**.

Postgraduate Module in Software Development

Open University. UK (Online, remote) [2019]

Analysis, design, software construction and testing; engage with various design practices from **design patterns** to **software architectures** and **frameworks**. Course delivered in **Java**.

B.Sc. Digital Technology and Design

Dublin Institute of Technology

[2017 - 2018]

User Experience and Concept Design, Mobile and Web Applications, Server-Side Web Development, Web and Device Programming. Learned HTML, CSS, Javascript, Php and MySQL along with Angular, jQuery, Codeignitor, Phonegap & Wordpress.

B.Sc. Applied Physics and Instrumentation

Cork Institute of Technology

[2011 - 2014]

50% practical based with a strong emphasis on process control, quality and safety systems. **Event driven programming** with **VB.net**, as well as programming with the **Siemens s7 PLC** and the **Emerson DeltaV** automation system. **Visual programming** with **LabView** as well as various Math & Physics modules.

RELEVANT WORK EXPERIENCE

Serve.ie - Web Developer (Remote, part-time)

[2021 - Current]

➤ Redesign, optimize & maintain serve.ie. Automate the maintenance, implement SEO, manage the hosting, domains and e-mails.

DEITG I.T. Generalists - Web Developer

[2018-2019] (18 Months)

- ➤ Designed, developed, deployed, tested, secured, maintained and updated 50+ websites and web apps.
- ➤ Designed and developed the frontend of large web apps using CakePhp & CSS.
- > Successfully improved the company's website SEO to attract new customers for all services.
- ➤ Greatly reduced technical debt and set up automated monthly updates to keep all websites easily manageable.

Other Skills

Git + GitHub
Agile (Scrum)
Web Design
UX & UI
NPM
SEO
Domains & Hosting
Google Suite
Web Performance
Web Security
PC Building
Java (Academic)
Pokemon Master

Contact

PHONE: +13262611753

GITHUB:

<u>https://github.com/davidma</u> <u>son5</u>

LINKEDIN:

https://www.linkedin.com/in/david-mason-1623277b/

EMAIL:

daveymason@outlook.com

OTHER WORK EXPERIENCE

Hills Kindy - Homeroom Teacher

[2020 - Current]

- ➤ Homeroom teacher for an international kindergarten in my wife's hometown of TiaYuan.
- ➤ Develop STEM based lessons to teach students the basics of English, math and computer science.

TaiYuan University of Technology - English Teacher [2019-2020]

- Created an LMS for students to continue to learn during lockdown from COVID-19.
- ➤ Delivered online classes on a weekly basis to help students improve their English listening skills.

DEITG I.T. Generalists - Web Developer

[2018–2019] (Previous page)

B.Sc. Digital Technology and Design - Student *Dublin Institute of Technology* [2016-2018] (Previous page)

Various Schools in China - Teacher [2014-2016]

- ➤ Worked with an agency to teach in primary and secondary schools in various locations in China.
- ➤ Subjects included English, Math & Science to various grades.
- ➤ Some roles included curriculum design & implementation.

Cork Institute of Technology - Student Support [2013-2014]

- Provided a range of community building services including an information desk & weekly institute newsletter.
- > Designed posters and newsletters using Photoshop & MS Office.
- ➤ Organized charity events for daffodil day and assisted with Students Union charity events.
- ➤ Focal point of contact for international students solving all sorts of problems they had living and studying in Ireland.